I remember the magic spell
From back when a rainbow stretched across the sky
In an instant, every corner of the world
Took on a brilliant hue
The voice of my heart
Always illuminates the path I need to take
It is because I doubt everything
That I know it to be true
Why does my heart still beat?
Why do my lungs still breathe?
Why is my chest burning with passion?
There's a reason for all of that
And, like the starry sky hidden behind the clouds
Like the ticket to a destination I lost somewhere
Like the history of the world from before I was born
You hold the answer just beyond my reach
If nothing else, I know that all too well
If nobody else, I know that all too well
Child of God (Part One)
Without thinking, it came out of my mouth.
（桐山(きりやま) 零(れい)）
思わず口から こぼれ落ちてた
I want to go somewhere.
（零）どこか行きたい…
Huh?
（川本(かわもと)ひなた）えっ？ どこどこ？
零君　どこ行きたいの？
Where?
Where do you want to go, Rei?
What's that? Would you let me nibble a bit?
Um, as for where I'd like to go...
えっとね 私はね
It's gotta be Milkyland, right?
ミルキーランドでしょ？
あと江ノ島でしょ？
And Enoshima, right?
あっ 後ね 中華街！ 横浜の！
And Chinatown in Yokohama!
With meat dumplings,
shrimp in chili sauce, and almond jelly!
肉まんとか えびチリとか
杏仁(あんにん)豆腐(どうふ)とか… きゃ〜い
Yahoo-ey!
I wanna dig for potatoes!
（モモ）
モモはね モモはね！ 芋掘り！
後ね おしょうゆ工場！
And then, a soy sauce factory!
Why, Momo? You already went there on a field trip, didn't you?
（川本相米二(そめじ)）んー？ 何だ モモ
そりゃ
お前の遠足で行った所だろ？
You have to say the places you want to go.
行きたい所だよ　行きたい所
Looks like she had a lot of fun digging up potatoes.
（川本あかり）
よっぽど楽しかったのね 芋掘り
She's been talking about it ever since.
ずっと言ってるもんね
お姉ちゃんは どこ行きたいの？
Where do you want to go, Sis?
Let's see...
そうね〜 海がきれいで
のーんびりできる所かなぁ
How about a place with a beautiful beach,
where I can relax?
I'd take a nap, go to a beauty salon,
or maybe get an aromatherapy massage.
お昼寝したり
エステとかアロママッサージとか…
あー でも…
But I'd be happy if the meals just
came out without saying anything.
黙ってても ごはんが
出てくるだけで幸せかも
ふぅ… うふふ
（零･相米二）
いつも お世話になっております！
Thank you for always taking care of us!
As for me, well...
（相米二）俺は うん そうだなぁ
やっぱり お伊勢(いせ)さんかなぁ
I suppose the Ise Grand Shrine.
Your grandmother wanted to go there too.
ばあさんも
行ってみたいって言ってたし
So, kid...
んで… 坊主
お前 どこ行きてえんだ？
Where do you want to go?
（零）そう言われてやっと気付いた
I finally realized after being asked.
That I didn't have a place I wanted to go.
行きたい所なんて無いってことに
どうやら僕は どこかに
行きたかったのではなく—
It seems that I didn't want to go to anywhere in particular.
I just wanted to go somewhere else.
どこかへ行ってしまいたかった
ということらしいのだ
I guess that's what it was.
So for the study camp, Kiriyama will be marked as absent.
（林田(はやしだ)高志(たかし)）それじゃ 桐山は
今年の移動教室には不参加と…
I'm sure you must be busy with
your class-promotion tournament.
まぁ
順位戦じゃ しょうがないよなぁ
お前 もうプロだし 仕事だからな
You're already a pro, so it's your job.
（零）対局は絶対で
Matches are absolute, so forfeiting isn't acceptable, except to attend your parents' funeral.
２親等までの葬式等以外での
棄権は認められない
It's really a shame you can't attend.
（林田）でも 残念だよなぁ
移動教室ったら 学生時代の
一大イベントなんだけどなぁ
Study camps are a major event in a student's life.
Yeah.
はい
（零）確かに
僕は少々がっかりしていた
True, I was a little disappointed.
参加できなかったことにではなく
I wasn't disappointed that I couldn't go.
I was disappointed in myself for being
secretly relieved at getting out of going.
行かずに済むことに
内心ほっとした自分にだ
Still...
（林田）しっかしなー
（零）ん？
You could at least try to hide the relief on your face.
そんな あからさまに
ほっとした顔してくれるなよ
Crap. He saw through me.
（零）しまった　読まれてた
（零）そんな 顔に もろ出てたのか
Was it that obvious?
Look, I know how you feel.
やぁ そりゃあ分かるけどな
お前 友達いないし
You don't have any friends,
and suddenly being thrown in with a group of guys you've never talked to before
こんなときだけ
いきなり しゃべったことも
ないようなやつらの—
グループに放り込まれて
and then having to sleep in the same room for four nights is going to be tough.
雑魚寝で４泊５日は
確かに きついっちゃ
かなりきついだろうけどさぁー
Um, Mr. Hayashida, can we be a bit more subtle?
ていうか 先生　包みましょうよ
もっとこうオブラートに
Maybe a little more tactful, and not so straightforward.
ストレートすぎますよ
ふー まっ プロ棋士に
Well, I know a professional shogi player doesn't have much free time.
余分な時間が無いのは
分かるけどな
（零）
確かに 対局は月に数回だが
True, I do have several matches a month.
それは 野球や
ボクシングでいうところの—
Shogi is like a baseball or boxing tournament in that respect.
試合と同じようなもので
So what does a professional athlete do on their "day off"?
じゃあ スポーツ選手が
試合のない日に 何をしているか
Yes, the answer is training.
そう　答えはトレーニング
棋士もスポーツ選手も同じ
Shogi players are like professional athletes in that regard.
試合のない日は
練習や勉強をしているのだ
On days without matches, we practice or study.
先人たちの残した 星の数ほどの
棋譜を調べ 並べてみたり
We examine and set up the countless
match records left behind by predecessors,
hold study sessions with fellow shogi players, investigate new tactics together...
同じ棋士仲間で 研究会を行って
新しい戦法を検討し合ったり
But then I don't see the reason why you bothered to re-enroll in high school.
（林田）
うん でも これじゃあ お前
何のために 高校 入り直したのか
分かんないなぁ
You have a point.
ですよね？
え〜っ！
おい あっさり認めるなよー
What?!
Hey, don't admit it so easily.
（幸田(こうだ)香子(きょうこ)）
家も無いし 家族も無い
You don't have a home.
You don't have a family.
You don't go to school.
学校にも行ってない
友達もいない
You don't have any friends.
There's no place for you in this world.
あなたの居場所なんて
この世の どこにも無いじゃない
（零）香子の言葉は 心の
ど真ん中に飛び込んできたが
Kyouko's words jumped right into the center of my heart,
怒りも悲しみも湧き起こらず—
but they didn't make me angry or sad.
I simply thought, "That's just how it is."
ただただ そのとおりだと思った
That's exactly why I wanted to turn pro.
だからこそ
プロになりたいと思った
I thought if I could support myself without any help,
自分の力だけで
生活することができれば
that would become the "place where I belong."
そこが 自分の居場所に
なるんじゃないかと思った
So I desperately latched onto the shogi board.
そう思って
必死に盤に食らいついてきた
そして その夢は かなって
現実となり
Then, that dream came true and became my reality.
（零）
荷物は ほとんど無かったので
引っ越しは あっけなく済んだ
I didn't have many possessions, so my move didn't take long.
それから しばらくの間は
カーテンもテレビも無い部屋で
For some time after that, it was like my battery had run out as I sat in a room without curtains or a TV.
まるで電池が切れたみたいに
対局と 時々学校に行く以外では
毎日毎日 ただ眠り続けた
Other than matches and sometimes going to school,
I would spend the days sleeping away.
I don't know why, but I would get so
sleepy every day that I couldn't help it.
なぜだか 毎日 眠くて眠くて
どうしようもなかった
家事は 前の家で手伝っていたので
ひととおりできたけど
In my previous home, I helped out with the chores, so I more-or-less continued doing them.
自分一人だけのためには
But when you're doing it for yourself, it's a hassle to even cook some rice,
ごはんを炊くことすら
めんどくさくて
so I stopped.
しなくなった
The first year was fine.
１年目は良かった
I moved forward with the money I'd saved up until then.
今まで積み上げてきたものの貯金で
前へ進めた
There are currently 30 people in Class C1.
Ｃ級１組は 現在30人
そのうち10人と対戦をして—
Each person faces off against ten opponents in the class.
The two people with the most wins can advance to B2.
勝ち星が多い順に ２名だけが
Ｂ級２組に昇級できる
Advancing requires winning every match, or at least winning nearly all of them.
昇級には 全勝か
それに近い勝ち星が必要だった
しかし ２年目の今年…
初めて２連敗を食らった
But in my second year, this year,
I lost two matches in a row for the first time.
And while I sat dumbfounded,
そして ぼう然としているうちに
昇級する目を失った
I lost my chance at promotion.
I swam...
（零）泳いで…
and swam...
泳いで…
泳いで… 泳いで… 泳いで…
and swam...
泳いで… 泳いで…
泳ぎ抜いた果てに—
and swam to the end.
I finally made it to the island.
やっと たどり着いた島
（零）
ここまで来れば もう大丈夫だ
If I've come this far, I should be okay.
（零）ここにさえ着けば…
As long as I got here...
ここにさえ居続けられれば…
As long as I could stay here...
As long as I didn't wish for this or that...
あれもこれもと
多くを望まなければ
As long as I accepted stagnation...
停滞を受け入れてしまえば
As long as I stopped thinking...
思考を停止してしまえれば
もう ここはゴールで…
then I'd reached my goal.
And I no longer had any reason to plunge back into that stormy sea and head for the next island.
そして もう一度
嵐の海に飛び込んで—
次の島に向かう理由を
僕はもう既に
何一つ持ってなかった
Child of God (Part One)
Child of God (Part Two)
He had such a cold name.
（零）なんて寒そうな
名前なんだろう
That's what I thought when I first saw him.
初めて見た時 そう思った
But I can't remember when that was.
でも その初めてが いつだったか
思い出せない
（零）そのくらい ずっと前から
当たり前にそこに在った
He just naturally existed there for that long of a time.
Souya Touji.
宗谷(そうや)冬司(とうじ)…
僕たちの国の 神様の子供
In our world, he was the child of God.
You don't have that soccer ball-looking rice ball today.
（林田）
今日は サッカーボールみたいな
あのおにぎりじゃないんだな
Mr. Hayashida.
（零）先生…
（林田）
さすがに もう外は寒いか
It's too cold to sit outside, huh?
But it's pretty cold here too, isn't it?
でも ここだって寒いだろ？
かなり
んっふふふ… 桐山
見てくれ これ
Kiriyama, take a look at this.
んふふふ…
新しい「将棋現代」
The newest edition of Modern Shogi.
Tokyo
Made by Hayashida Takashi
Intermediate
Level
載っちゃった「詰め将棋交差点」
I made the "Shogi Checkmate Problems" section!
Oh, yeah.
（零）あっ ほんとだ
すごいじゃないですか
That's great.
わぁ なかなか
きれいに出来てますね
Ah, it's set up very neatly.
B*3a, K-2c, G*1c, Nx1c, B-3c+, K-1d, Bx1c+, Kx1c, G*2c, K-1d, N*2f, Gx2f, N-2d.
Easy-peasy...
２四馬まで 13手詰めですね
Checkmate in thirteen moves.
Easy-peasy...
Easy-peasy
Waaaaah
That was fast!
早っ！ 作るの１週間
解くのは一瞬？
A week to create,
yet a moment to solve?!
で… ですよねー
プ… プロですものねー
I-I guess so, since you're a p-pro.
（零）あ…
（林田）宗谷名人か
Oh, Master Souya.
He's doing great this season too.
すごいなー 今期も
He's already successfully defended his Shogi God,
Sacred Dragon, and King titles.
棋神　聖竜　玉将
もう既に３つ防衛かぁ
どんな人なんだ？
What's he like?
I wonder that too.
（零）どんな人なんでしょうね
You've never met?
（林田）会ったことないのか？
同じプロでも
Even though you're both pros?
I haven't met him, but I have seen him around.
（零）会ったというより
見たことなら…
Special
Match Room
クラスも違うし
We're in different classes,
and Master Souya currently holds most of the titles.
今 タイトルは ほとんど
宗谷名人が持ってるから
Even at tournaments, I rarely see him.
トーナメントで会うことも もう
ほぼ ないですし
This guy's the same age as me.
俺と同い年なんだよなぁ この人
But his looks haven't changed since he was a teenager.
でも 10代のころから全然
顔が変わんないんだよ
なんかこう
時間が止まってるっていうか…
It's like time has stopped for him.
Such a strange thing.
不思議なんだよなあ
I think the first time I saw him was in junior high in a special feature called, "A Junior High Professional is Born."
初めて見たのは
俺が中学生ん時の—
「中学生プロ誕生」
って特集だったっけ
お？ そうだ！ そういや
お前のこと初めて見たのも—
Oh, that's right.
Come to think of it, the first time I saw you was in the same kind of feature in this magazine.
The 5th in History
A Junior High Professional
この本の同じ特集でだったっけ
Oh, I see.
あ〜 そっかぁ
こうやって目の前に居ると
忘れちゃうけど
When you're right in front of me, I tend to forget, but you're actually an amazing person.
お前 ほんとは
すごいやつなんだよな〜
独りぼっちでポツーンと
昼飯 食ってるけど
Even though you sit here all alone eating lunch.
ここでは ほんと
居るか居ないか分からないけど
And even though I don't know if you're here at school or not.
Again, Mr. Hayashida, if you could be a little more tactful.
（零）先生　だから もうちょっと
オブラートにくるんで…
（零）将棋界の歴史の中で
In the history of shogi, there have only been four players who turned professional as junior high students.
中学生でプロになった人間は
今まで たったの４人
そして その４人は その後—
And afterward, those four either
became a Master or won other titles.
全て 名人になるか
タイトルを取っている
But as the fifth such person...
けれど その５人目である僕は…
We anticipate great things.
（将棋関係者Ａ）期待してますよ
They're already calling you the "Future Master."
あなたは 未来の名人と
言われてるんですから
（将棋関係者Ｂ）天才も
たまには不調くらいあるよねぇ
Sometimes even prodigies go through a slump.
Hey, what gives? You better get it together.
（将棋関係者Ａ）
おいおい どうしちゃったのさ
しっかりしてよ
未来の名人なんだからさあ
Remember, you're the "Future Master."
（将棋関係者Ｂ）
天才とか言われて いい気に
なっちゃってるんじゃないの？
Did you get full of yourself after people called you a prodigy?
I'm...
（零）僕は…
すごくないです
全然すごくないんです
I'm not amazing.
I'm not amazing at all.
Flap
（林田）ほれ！ やるよ カツ！
Here. I'll give this to you. Cutlet!
Flap
You know, it's that.
ほら あれだ
〝勝負に勝つ〞ってね
Cut-let yourself to victory!
…じゃないなぁ
Maybe not.
多分 この場合は“己に勝つ”だな
Maybe in this case...
you need to win from yourself.
Yeah.
Oh, I see. He's referring to my consecutive defeats.
（零）ああ そうか
先生 連敗のこと…
Anyway, it'll be even colder next month, you know?
（林田）さてっとー
なぁ 桐山
来月んなったら もっと寒いぞ
You should start eating in the classroom...
お前も そろそろ
教室で食べられるように…
Although, I guess you'd stand out if you ate by yourself in class.
つっても
教室で一人で食べるってのも—
目立っちゃって あれかなぁ
つらいよな
That's tough.
See, Mr. Hayashida, if you could candy-coat it a bit...
だから 先生
オブラートに包んで… って
T
h
i
n
s
m
i
l
e
Oh, I get it. Your sense of subtlety must be broken.
あはは そっか
破けてるんですね
先生のオブラートって
きっと…
That's it.
Oh! I could eat lunch in class with you.
（林田）あっ じゃ俺が
一緒に食ってやろうか？
（零）先生
余計 目立つと思うんです
I think I would stand out even more like that.
（林田）桐山はな
試験の成績はいいんだけどなぁ
Kiriyama, you get good grades on tests,
but you didn't come back to high school because you wanted to study.
でも お前が もっかい
学校に入ってきたのって—
勉強がしたかったからじゃ
ないよな？ 多分…
I think.
（零）言い当てられて
何も言えなかった
He guessed it correctly, so I couldn't respond.
In November, after suffering my third loss,
11月 僕に３つ目の黒星が付いて
墨を飲んだような気持ちになった
I felt like I'd swallowed black ink.
I understand it in my head, so why can I do nothing about it?
頭では分かっているのに
動けないのは何でだ？
勝つ理由が無いとか言いながら
負けると苦しいのは なぜだ？
I say I have no reason to win,
so why is it so painful when I lose?
I always take half-measures...
中途半端だ 僕は
with everything.
何もかも…
（ひなた）あっ 零ちゃん？
（零）あっ
Rei?
（零）ヒナちゃん
（ひなた）零ちゃんも商店街？
Hina.
Are you going to the shopping district too?
Oh, uh...
Me too. I'm going to the bookstore.
（ひなた）
私もね 本屋さん 行くんだ
一緒に行かない？
Want to go together?
零ちゃん　最近 来ないね
You haven't come over recently, huh?
We had dumplings last night.
ゆうべ ギョーザだったんだよ
皮から作ったの
Even the wrappers were homemade.
すごく おいしかったんだから
They were so delicious.
You should've come.
来れば良かったのに
Yeah. I guess so.
うん　そっか…
Shiny
（零）買ったげようか？
I could buy it for you.
Huh?!
え〜っ！ いいよ！ 悪いしー
No, I'd feel bad!
That's all right. It's only 100 yen.
（零）いや いいよ 全然
100円だし…
は… はわわ〜
All right.
（零）はい どうぞ
Here you go.
First time being
treated by a guy.
あ… ありがとう
Th-Thank you!
It's cold! And really thick! But yummy!
Siiip
Gulp
（ひなた）冷たっ！ 固っ！
でも おいし〜い！
Gulp
零ちゃん やっぱり…
元気ない
As I thought, Rei...
looks glum.
Rei was crying.
零ちゃん 泣いてた
涙が ぽーろぽーろしてた
Big tears drip-dropped down his cheeks.
（あかり）
きっと 思い出しちゃったんだね
I'm sure it's because he remembered something sad.
Rei hasn't come over recently, huh?
零ちゃん 最近 来ないね
True.
そうね　でも今は 少し
そっとしといてあげましょう
But let's give him a little space for now.
Everyone has times when they want to be alone.
そういうときも あるものよ
That's what Sis said, but...
（ひなた）お姉ちゃんは
ああ言っていたけれど…
But!
だけど…
Want some?!
（ひなた）飲む？
（零）えっ？
What?
Listen, we're having tempura tonight.
あのね 今日は天ぷらなの
かぼちゃとか 玉ねぎとか
Like with pumpkin and onions!
お姉ちゃんが揚げると
すっごくおいしいの
And when Sis deep fries them, they're so delicious!
So...
だから…
Rei is always quiet and mature like an adult,
（ひなた）零ちゃんは
いつも静かで大人っぽいけれど
but I know he cries sometimes, so I worry about him.
でも 泣き虫なところもあるから
心配なの
だから… だから…
So...
You should come over!
うちにおいでよ！
Let's eat dinner together.
一緒にごはん食べよ！
Child of God (Part Two)
Like a resplendent meteor shower
Your words enter my ears and catch fire
They come together like a school of fish
And form a warm corner in my once chilly bosom
As I stood in place, not knowing the right way to reach out
Your hand reached out to touch mine
And no matter how many nights may pass
That warmth still lingers and pulses within
Your very presence shines a bright light on every part of my life
Your racing heartbeat resonates with my frozen heart and sets it ablaze
Before long, the fire dies out
Leaving just one smoldering ember
Which remains with me and won't ever go away
Living inside of me in a place closest to my heart
Child of God (Part Three)
You should come over!
（ひなた）うちにおいでよ！
（零）あ… はい
Okay.
That's good.
良かった
（零）改めて思った
It struck me again how this tiny girl
named Hina is so kind and level-headed.
この ヒナちゃんという子は
小さいけど優しくて—
とてもしっかりしているのだ
Still, a junior high student worrying about a high school student is so...
でも 中学生に心配される
高校生って 一体…
That's right.
そうだ
ヒナちゃんは妹の面倒を見て
Hina takes care of her little sister,
helps with the chores, and helps out at the store.
家のことも手伝って
お店の手伝いもして
Even Akari takes proper care of all of them.
あかりさんなんて
みんなの世話をきちんとして
She helps out at both the sweets shop and her aunt's hostess club in Ginza.
和菓子屋さんの方も
銀座の叔母さんの店も手伝って
Everyone is working so hard.
みんな
ものすごい頑張っているのに…
That's right.
そうだよな
何で俺は 俺のことだけで
How is it that my head fills up so fast...
with only my own problems?
すぐ いっぱいいっぱいに
なってしまってるんだろう
It's pathetic.
情けない
Gerrg
Blush
ヒナちゃん？
Hina?
Gerrg?
Crunch
（高橋(たかはし)勇介(ゆうすけ)）おう 川本
Hey, Kawamoto.
Oh, it's the guy from the baseball game.
（零）あ… あの時の
ヒナちゃんの好きな…
The one Hina has a crush on.
Looming
danger
（零）あっ えーと お友達かな？
ここ どうぞ
Um, you must be a friend of hers, right?
Please, have my seat.
I was just about to leave.
僕は もう行くんで… ん？
Squeeze
Kablam
うっはっは〜！ わっわあ〜！
Massive
Already
around
180 cm tall
Already
around
180 cm tall
Massive
（零）わー
き… 気まずい
Massive
This is awkward...
Silence...
Massive
Um... Uh...
あの ええっと…
Massive
（零）な… 何を
話したらいいのかしら？
Wh-What do I talk about?
スポーツマンとなんて
話したことないよー
I've never talked to an athlete before.
Stare
To Be Continued
Next Episode Preview
Episode 7
（高橋）
久しぶりだな 川本んち
Man, it's been a while since I've come here.
He's huge... I'm scared!
（零）でかい… 怖い…
Do you think curry will be enough?
（ひなた）ほんとに
カレーで良かったのかな？
（あかり）じゃ…
じゃあ おまけで—
Okay, then how about deep-fried
chicken as an extra topping?
から揚げをトッピング
ってのは どうよ？
Thank you, Sis!
（ひなた）お姉ちゃん
ありがとう！
（相米二）
青春っぽいじゃねえか
こんちくしょーい！
Ah, youth! I'm jealous, dammit!
Hey, let's have curry already.
（モモ）ねぇ ねぇ
カレー 早く食べよ！
Illustration: Shibata Yokusaru
（あかり）
３月のライオン
次回も御覧くださいね！
I hope you watch the next episode of
"March comes in like a lion"!
The beach is nice too,
but I also want to go to a hot spring!
海もいいけど
温泉もいいわよね〜